Guide to the Rob Amberg photographs and papers, 1975-2009 and undated RL.00031
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- The New Road: I-26 and the Footprints of Progress, 1978-2004, 8 boxes
  - Loose Prints, 1978-2004
    - Advertising sign for the new Wingate Inn, Bear Branch, Madison County, N.C., 2003 (Box 12, Image #03034-13)
    - Warning sign on US-23 at the Tennessee/North Carolina state line, Sams Gap, Madison County, N.C., 1998 (Box 12, Image #98035-2)
    - North Carolina Department of Transportation Geologist Rick Lockamy and his crew searching for center-line flags, Sprinkle Creek, Madison County, N.C., 1994 (Box 12, Image #940065-31)
    - Horseshoe outline on barn, Little Creek, Madison County, N.C., 1997 (Box 12, Image #970073-25)
    - Bench used to grade tobacco, Little Creek, Madison County, N.C., 1997 (Box 12, Image #970074-33)
    - Remains of an abandoned car, Little Creek, Madison County, N.C., 1998 (Box 12, Image #98060-10)
    - North Carolina Department of Transportation writing on barn floor, Little Creek, Madison County, N.C., 1997 (Box 12, Image #970074-32)
    - Remains of the Liquor House, Buckner Gap, Madison County, N.C., 1995 (Box 12, Image #950010-33)
    - Flagged graves at the Higgins Branch Cemetery, Higgins Branch, Madison County, N.C., 1995 (Box 12, Image #950140-7)
    - Grave of Calvin Wiley George in the Little Ivy Church Cemetery, Mars Hill, Madison County, N.C., 1996 (Box 12, Image #960126-19)
    - Family yard sale, Poplar Cove, Madison County, N.C., 1997 (Box 12, Image #970074-1)
- The Sodom Laurel Album, 1975-2001, 3 boxes
  Consists of 131 8x10 black and white prints. Subjects include tobacco farming and rural life in Madison County, North Carolina from the mid-1970s through the early 1990s. The majority of the prints follow the lives of Dellie and Junior Norton who farmed tobacco in the county. Dellie Norton was also an accomplished folk singer. Original captions and numbering taken from back of prints.
  - Clinton Norton and his Robin doll, 1977 (Box 13, Image #77043-16)
  - Charles Chandler, 1978 (Box 13, Image #80011-38)
  - Junior walking Pet to water, 1979 (Box 13, Image #79014-2)
  - The first picture I made of Junior, 1975 (Box 13, Image #75002-10)
  - Clinton and Junior on Dellie's porch, 1977 (Box 13, Image #77089-8)
  - Tillman Chandler's barn and tobacco crop, 1975 (Box 13, Image #75-)
  - At Ramsey's Store, 1977 (Box 13, Image #77090-11)
  - Dellie doing laundry on the side porch, 1975 (Box 13, Image #75005-14)
  - Dellie and Junior, 1978 (Box 13, Image #78068-11)
  - Ku Klux Klan rally, 1976 (Box 13, Image #76-KKK)
  - Joyce Chandler, Joe Ross Chandler's wife, 1976 (Box 13, Image #76066-22)
  - Dellie's grandson, Joe Ross Chandler, 1976 (Box 13, Image #76053-26)
  - Jim Wallin holding a royalty check for a song he wrote, 1977 (Box 13, Image #77077-11)
  - Dellie's great-granddaughter, Denice Chandler, in her front yard, 1977 (Box 13, Image #77088-10)
  - Martha and Joe's trailer, 1977 (Box 13, Image #77091-9)
  - Donald Norton and his sons, Donavan (left) and Donnie (right), 1977 (Box 13, Image #77087-4)
  - Clinton Norton waiting for the school bus, 1977 (Box 13, Image #77101-)
  - Delline Norton in her living room, 1977 (Box 13, Image #77037-13)
  - Inez Chandler holding her Christening dress, 1977 (Box 13, Image #77058-6)
  - Junior in the living room, 1976 (Box 13, Image #76033-17)
  - Dellie topping and suckering tobacco, 1976 (Box 13, Image #7601-R45-17)
  - Junior hoeing tobacco, 1976 (Box 13, Image #76023-34)
  - Dellie's grandson, Carry Norton, taking a break from plowing tobacco, 1975 (Box 13, Image #75005-5)
  - McKinley Massey and neighbors planting tobacco, 1982 (Box 13, Image #82011-23)
  - Doyle Roberts pulling tobacco plants, 1989 (Box 13, Image #89099-25)
  - Charlie Massey spraying tobacco ground with pesticides and herbicides, 1982 (Box 13, Image #82009-21A)
  - Junior plowing in the Teat Holler, 1975 (Box 13, Image #7500-)
  - Dellie milking her cow, 1977 (Box 13, Image #77105-4)
  - Dellie's calf, 1977 (Box 13, Image #77081-23)
  - Dellie's pig, 1977 (Box 13, Image #77081-22)
  - Junior and the Jumping Cat, 1975 (Box 13, Image #75013-1)
  - Dellie taking a break from hauling tobacco, 1976 (Box 13, Image #76061-18)
  - The fuel oil barrel, 1978 (Box 13, Image #78083-23)
  - The woodshed, 1978 (Box 13, Image #78083-20)
  - The wall in Junior's bedroom, 1977-1978 (Box 13, Image #77086-26)
  - The wall in Junior's bedroom, 1977-1978 (Box 13, Image #77086-28)
  - Dellie fixing food for her pets, 1977 (Box 13, Image #77085-25)
  - Junior repairing the spring, 1976 (Box 13, Image #76023-17)
  - The shed and pear tree in Dellie's yard, 1977 (Box 13, Image #77005-3)
  - Ben Amberg, Rob's son, with Dellie and Junior, 1982 (Box 13, Image #82013-26)
  - Dellie at the kitchen door, 1975 (Box 13, Image #75006-3)
  - Dellie's family at Ft. Leonard Wood, Missouri, 1979 (Box 13, Image #79023-1)
  - Driving to Sodom over Walnut Mountain and through Walnut Gap, 2001 (Box 13, Image #01069-9)
  - Isaac Gunter's tobacco field and cemetery, 1982 (Box 13, Image #82025-22)
  - Pavement Ends sign on Eastern Gap Road, 1977 (Box 13, Image #77114-9)
  - Wotch For Cattle sign on Eastern Gap Road, 1979 (Box 13, Image #79040-9)
  - Junior walking to the house from the barn, 1976 (Box 13, Image #7601-R05-7A)
  - Dellie at the kitchen door, 1976 (Box 13, Image #76044-9A)
  - The guest bedroom wall in Dellie's house, 1977-1978 (Box 13, Image #78059-18)
  - The wall in Dellie's bedroom, 1977-1978 (Box 13, Image #78062-23)
  - Spreading out wet tobacco leaves to dry at the warehouse, 1988 (Box 14, Image #88018-16)
  - At the main entrance to Planter Warehouse, 1994 (Box 14, Image #940166-23)
  - Warehouse worker unloading tobacco, 1981 (Box 14, Image #81031-17)
  - Handed burley tobacco, 1983 (Box 14, Image #83062)
  - Dellie tying tobacco leaves into hands, 1976 (Box 14, Image #76060-9)
  - Junior in the barn, 1977 (Box 14, Image #77133-16)
  - Contact sheet of Junior in barn with tobacco, 1977 (Box 14, Image #77133)
  - Junior photographing Dellie, David Holt, and Zeb Holt, 1978 (Box 14, Image #78063-21)
  - Junior holding "Hippie from Mississippi" photograph, 1984 (Box 14, Image #84003-13)
  - Junior hauling corn fodder, 1976 (Box 14, Image #76057-16)
  - Junior holding ginseng, 1977 (Box 14, Image #78083-26)
  - Junior getting a shave and haircut, 1986 (Box 14, Image #86004-27)
  - Junior holding hoe, 1977 (Box 14, Image #77127-15)
  - Junior, 1975 (Box 14, Image #75001-11)
  - Junior and shadow, 1981 (Box 14, Image #81002-1)
  - Junior, 1979 (Box 14, Image No Image Number)
  - Junior, 1979 (Box 14, Image #79004-)
  - Junior at the upper house after Dellie moved, 1979 (Box 14, Image #79004-6)
  - Junior as the "Hippie from Mississippi," 1976 (Box 14, Image No Image Number)
  - Junior at the High Rock, 1976 (Box 14, Image #76052-17)
  - Junior in my Marshall studio, 1983 (Box 14, Image #83022-84)
  - On Dellie's porch, 1978 (Box 14, Image #78063-30)
  - Filming "Amazing Grace: America in Song" on Dellie's porch, 1975 (Box 14, Image No Image Number)
  - Playing setback on Dellie's porch, 1977 (Box 14, Image #77085-7)
  - Dellie combing her hair, 1978 (Box 14, Image #78064-12)
  - Dellie's daughter, Mary Norton, 1977 (Box 14, Image #77081-)
  - Dellie stringing beans while Nancy Morris plays guitar, 1975 (Box 14, Image #75016-7)
  - Dellie dancing on Dellie's porch, 1978 (Box 14, Image #78064-3)
  - Dellie's porch, 1978 (Box 14, Image #78083-7)
  - Junior on the porch, 1977 (Box 14, Image #77080-1)
  - Dellie and pet and tobacco, 1977 (Box 14, Image #77105-6)
  - Augie Shelton and family picking up tobacco leaves, 1983 (Box 14, Image #83053-1)
  - Hoy Shelton and family hanging tobacco, 1983 (Box 14, Image #83053-)
  - Juanita Shelton hauling tobacco to the barn, 1983 (Box 14, Image #83053-5A)
  - Augie and Juanita Shelton unloading tobacco, 1983 (Box 14, Image #83053-9A)
  - 16 year old Augie Shelton unloading tobacco, 1983 (Box 14, Image #83053)
  - Juanita Shelton guiding truck load of tobacco to the barn, 1983 (Box 14, Image #83057-37)
  - Migrant farmworker hauling tobacco to the truck, 1993 (Box 14, Image #93135-30)
  - Cut burley tobacco, 1993 (Box 14, Image #93136-42)
  - Migrant farmworker cutting and spudding tobacco, 1993 (Box 14, Image #93135-26)
  - Junior riding sled to the field to haul in tobacco, 1976 (Box 14, Image #76056-5)
  - Clinton Norton and Dellie on her front porch, 1977 (Box 14, Image #77089-11)
  - Joe Ross Chandler and Bobby Cantrell, 1977 (Box 14, Image #77124-21)
  - Joe Chandler, Dellie's son-in-law, and his son, Robert, 1976 (Box 14, Image #76061-12)
  - Mac Davis and neighbor butchering hog, 1975 (Box 14, Image #75023-6)
  - Jon Bullman and his cows, 1976 (Box 14, Image #76004-26)
  - Tildie making strawberry jam, 1994 (Box 14, Image #94055-1A)
  - Tildie Payar talking to her daughter, 1977 (Box 14, Image #77037-21)
  - Junior at Dellie's gravesite, 1993 (Box 15, Image #93128-4)
  - Junior at Dellie's funeral, 1993 (Box 15, Image #93131-6)
  - Dellie walking out to her porch, 1993 (Box 15, Image #93059-15)
  - Dellie cooking fierce, 1986 (Box 15, Image #86006-21)
  - Debbie Norton, Dellie's granddaughter, combing her hair, 1991 (Box 15, Image #91076-28)
  - Dellie at her 90th birthday party, 1988 (Box 15, Image #88098-4)
  - Junior tilling the garden at the lower house, 1986 (Box 15, Image #86014-12)
  - Junior in the living room of the upper house, 1990 (Box 15, Image #90016-1)
  - Dellie's wringer washer and the "Hippie from Mississippi" photo, 1990 (Box 15, Image #90016-4)
  - Dellie holding photograph of her father, Mart Chandler, 1993 (Box 15, Image #93027-25)
  - Dellie placing flowers on grave at Lump Mountain Cemetery, 1978 (Box 15, Image #78066-28)
  - Newly dug grave at Rice Cove Cemetery, 1977 (Box 15, Image #77097-18)
  - Preaching at Rice Cove Cemetery grave decoration, 1976 (Box 15, Image #76043-19)
  - Singing at Rice Cove Cemetery grave decoration, 1977 (Box 15, Image #77097-25)
  - At Chandler family reunion, 1976 (Box 15, Image #76040-33)
  - At Chandler family reunion, 1977 (Box 15, Image #77093-7)
  - Miky and Patty Chandler's wedding, 1978 (Box 15, Image #78028-24)
  - At Bonnie Chandler's wedding, 1978 (Box 15, Image #78001-27)
  - Willard Norton (left) and Patterson Wilde at Chandler family reunion, 1976 (Box 15, Image #76023-16)
  - Cas and Virgie Wallin, 1977 (Box 15, Image #77097-12)
  - Doug Wallin fiddling at home, 1977 (Box 15, Image #77105-25)
  - Berzilla dancing to Ernie Franklin's fiddling at his home, 1976 (Box 15, Image #76049-)
  - Dellie and Evelyn Ramsey singing at Eno River Festival, 1976 (Box 15, Image #76072-21)
  - Berzilla Wallin buckdancing at Eno River Festival, 1976 (Box 15, Image #76070)
  - Dellie and Berzilla singing at Marshall Elementary School, 1978 (Box 15, Image #78087-7)
  - Junior playing with my daughter Kate, 1992 (Box 15, Image #92009-10)
  - Zipporah Rice, Dellie's aunt, at home, 1976 (Box 15, Image #76034-20)
  - Liz Franklin in her home, 1975 (Box 15, Image #75027-8)
  - Berzilla Wallin in her living room holding photo of their family band, 1977 (Box 15, Image #77037-15)
  - Junior and Joe Chandler on Dellie's porch, 1977 (Box 15, Image No Image Number)
  - Janice Rice waiting for her tobacco check, 1994 (Box 15, Image #940176-32)
  - Warehouse worker loading purchased tobacco, 1981 (Box 15, Image #81009-26)
  - K. Stark bidding on tobacco crop, 1994 (Box 15, Image #940178-21)
- Vanishing Culture of Agriculture, 1984-1999, 4 boxes
  Consists of 87 11x14 black and white prints documenting agricultural life in North Carolina, Minnesota, Alabama, Kentucky, and South Carolina. Many of the images are from North Carolina and were part of an on-going assignment funded by the Rural Advancement Fund to document the rural Carolinas; others formed part of an annual report assigned and supported by the Mary Reynolds Babcock Foundation. Several images document organic farmers and their activities, and one of the last African-American dairy farmers in N.C. Original captions and numbering taken from back of prints. Arranged numerically by negative number.
  - Hazardous waste worker, Mitchell County, N.C., 1984 Fall (Box 16, Image #84048-22)
  - George Henry Lee and his hogs, Duplin County, N.C., 1986 Summer (Box 16, Image #860012-6)
  - Farmer herding his dairy cows, Orange County, N.C., 1986 Summer (Box 16, Image #860015-20)
  - Drought stricken corn, Iredell County, N.C., 1986 Summer (Box 16, Image #860026-0)
  - Farm organizer Charley Thompson talking with farmers, Harmony, Iredell County, N.C., 1986 Spring (Box 16, Image #860039-15)
  - Young farmers with their show sheep at the North Carolina State Fair, Raleigh, N.C., 1986 Fall (Box 16, Image #860043-9)
  - Farmer grooming his show cattle at the North Carolina State Fair, Raleigh, N.C., 1986 Fall (Box 16, Image #860046-27)
  - Show cows at the North Carolina State Fair, Raleigh, N.C., 1986 Fall (Box 16, Image #860046-30)
  - Poultry farmer George Ammons, Duplin County, N.C., 1986 Summer (Box 16, Image #860060-14)
  - Cotton gin worker, Bishopville, S.C., 1986 Fall (Box 16, Image #860063-34)
  - Cotton gin worker, Bishopville, S.C., 1986 Fall (Box 16, Image #860063-4)
  - Benny, Chall, and Catfish at Sam and Catherine Gray's farm near Marion, McDowell County, N.C., 1986 Summer (Box 16, Image #86019-5)
  - Farm estate auction, Bishopville, S.C., 1987 Winter (Box 16, Image #870006-10)
  - Abandoned country store, Lee County, S.C., 1987 Winter (Box 16, Image #870010-16)
  - Discarded herbicide and pesticide containers, Bishopville, S.C., 1987 Winter (Box 16, Image #870019-32)
  - George Henry Lee's turkeys, Magnolia, Duplin County, N.C., 1987 Winter (Box 16, Image #870022-25)
  - George Henry Lee inspecting his birds, Magnolia, Duplin County, N.C., 1987 Winter (Box 16, Image #870023-18)
  - Edna Harris herding cows to the milking parlor, Iredell County, N.C., 1987 Winter (Box 16, Image #870043-7)
  - Farmer Wilson Gerald talking with Rep. Pat Roberts at a meeting of Tobacco and Peanuts Subcommittee, Fayetteville, N.C., 1987 Spring (Box 16, Image #870056-4)
  - Farmers taking a break at George Henry Lee's store, Duplin County, N.C., 1987 Spring (Box 16, Image #870062-8)
  - Farm and cemetery, Iredell County, N.C., 1987 Spring (Box 16, Image #870064-9)
  - Cut hay field, Iredell County, N.C., 1987 Summer (Box 16, Image #870087-16)
  - Edna Harris repairing her hay bailer, Harmony, Iredell County, N.C., 1987 Summer (Box 17, Image #870102-6a)
  - Jim Smyre with his son and grand-daughter taking a break from setting tobacco, Harmony, Iredell County, N.C., 1987 Spring (Box 17, Image #870103-7)
  - Edna Harris, Iredell County, N.C., 1987 Summer (Box 17, Image #870104-27)
  - Edna Harris driving the hay bailer, Iredell County, N.C., 1987 Summer (Box 17, Image #870104-37)
  - Jim Smyre and family planting tobacco, Iredell County, N.C., 1987 Spring (Box 17, Image #870105-11)
  - Jim Smyre and his son planting tobacco, Iredell County, N.C., 1987 Spring (Box 17, Image #870105-25)
  - Retirees to the farm, Johnston County, N.C., 1987 Summer (Box 17, Image #870129-14)
  - Lonnie Harris moving cows to the milking parlor, Iredell County, N.C., 1987 Summer (Box 17, Image #870137-24)
  - Fence and gate on Edna Harris's farm, Iredell County, N.C., 1987 Summer (Box 17, Image #870138-10)
  - At the Harris family reunion, Iredell County, N.C., 1987 Summer (Box 17, Image #870145-29)
  - Donald Stokes teaching ESL to Haitian farm workers, Newton Grove, N.C., 1987 Summer (Box 17, Image #870147-16)
  - Haitian migrant farm workers learning English, Newton Grove, N.C., 1987 Summer (Box 17, Image #870147-20)
  - Carter Cosby selling his brother's watermelons, Clinton, N.C., 1987 Summer (Box 17, Image #870147-28)
  - Bunky feeding his chickens, Brunswick County, N.C., 1987 Summer (Box 17, Image #870160-16)
  - Chicken catcher putting chickens in pens for transport to slaughterhouse, Chatham County, N.C., 1987 Fall (Box 17, Image #870185-24)
  - Chicken catcher, Chatham County, N.C., 1987 Fall (Box 17, Image #870185-34)
  - Chickens leaving the farm for the slaughterhouse, Chatham County, N.C., 1987 Fall (Box 17, Image #870186-10)
  - Chicken catcher herding chickens, Chatham County, N.C., 1987 Fall (Box 17, Image #870186-16)
  - Farm worker collecting eggs, Chatham County, N.C., 1987 Winter (Box 17, Image #870191-33)
  - Tanese Wilson milking, Waco, N.C., 1987 Late Fall (Box 17, Image #870197-29)
  - Turkeys being loaded for the slaughterhouse, Duplin County, N.C., 1988 Winter (Box 17, Image #880013-22)
  - Turkeys being herded for transport to slaughterhouse, Duplin County, N.C., 1988 Winter (Box 17, Image #880013-26)
  - Jean and Ralph Wynont in their milking barn, Lawndale, N.C., 1988 Winter (Box 18, Image #880018-27)
  - Disabled dairyman, Lonnie Harris, Iredell County, N.C., 1988 Winter (Box 18, Image #880034-14)
  - Abandoned farm turned into a hunting club, Iredell County, N.C., 1989 Winter (Box 18, Image #890006-26)
  - Fourteen year old Salvadorian refugee collecting eggs in poultry breeder house, Iredell County, N.C., 1989 Spring (Box 18, Image #890030-33)
  - Salvadorian refugee cleaning eggs in breeder house, Iredell County, N.C., 1989 Spring (Box 18, Image #890032-23)
  - Sylvester Walker's grand-daughter playing basketball in his front yard, Spiveys Corner, N.C., 1989 Spring (Box 18, Image #890059-22)
  - Crossroads, Duplin County, N.C., 1989 Spring (Box 18, Image #890064-24)
  - Crossroads, Duplin County, N.C., 1989 Spring (Box 18, Image #890064-27)
  - Donald Stokes disking land, Duplin County, N.C., 1989 Summer (Box 18, Image #890064-7)
  - Construction work on I-40, Duplin County, N.C., 1989 Summer (Box 18, Image #890082-36)
  - On the road to Robert and Jane Peeble's house, Madison County, N.C., 1990 Summer (Box 18, Image #900062-18)
  - Farmer carrying peas to his truck, Eastern N.C., 1991 Summer (Box 18, Image #91037-15)
  - Farmer showing me her field peas, 1991 Summer (Box 18, Image #91037-27)
  - Dairyman Doug Wilson. At the time this photograph was made, Doug Wilson was one of three remaining black dairymen in North Carolina. He lost his arm to a silage cutting machine a few years earlier, but continued to farm, Waco, N.C., 1991 (Box 18, Image #91058-15)
  - Juanita Wilson and her mother, Waco, N.C., 1991 (Box 18, Image #91058-1a)
  - Doug Wilson's son feeding calves, Waco, N.C., 1991 (Box 18, Image #91059-28)
  - Rally for the victims of the Hamlet Poultry Plant fire, Hamlet, N.C., 1992 Spring (Box 18, Image #92033-40a)
  - Farmer feeding his free range hogs, Chatham County, N.C., 1993 (Box 18, Image #93044-5)
  - Girl selecting vegetables from Ken Dawson's stand at the Carrboro Farmers Market, Carrboro, N.C., 1993 Late spring (Box 18, Image #93076-28)
  - Farmer attending to sick hog, Chatham County, N.C., 1993 (Box 18, Image #93085-5)
  - Ken Dawson harvesting lettuce, Hillsborough, N.C., 1993 Fall (Box 18, Image #93164-16a)
  - Ken Dawson feeling his organic soil, Hillsborough, N.C., 1993 (Box 18, Image #93181-12a)
  - Farm worker family after egg collection, Samson, Ala., 1994 Winter (Box 19, Image #940015-5)
  - Chicken catcher loading birds for the slaughterhouse, Samson, Ala., 1994 Spring (Box 19, Image #940019-27)
  - Diane Tinsley and her baby chickens, Samson, Ala., 1994 Spring (Box 19, Image #940024-42)
  - Poultry barns, Samson, Ala., 1994 Spring (Box 19, Image #940026-14)
  - Ken Dawson inspecting his lettuce seedlings, Hillsborough, N.C., 1994 Summer (Box 19, Image #940117-15)
  - Ken Dawson building plant beds, Hillsborough, N.C., 1994 Spring (Box 19, Image #94118-11)
  - Heritage Day celebration, Manchester, Ky., 1995 Fall (Box 19, Image #950188-20)
  - Southern Minnesota Sugar Beet Cooperative, Granite Falls, Minn., 1995 Fall (Box 19, Image #950199-16)
  - Southern Minnesota Sugar Beet Cooperative, Granite Falls, Minn., 1995 Fall (Box 19, Image #950202-1)
  - Combine harvesting soybeans at night, Granite Falls, Minn., 1995 Fall (Box 19, Image #950206-11)
  - Combine harvesting soybeans at night, Granite Falls, Minn., 1995 Fall (Box 19, Image #950206-3)
  - Sacked sugar at worker-owned sugar beet cooperative, Granite Falls, Minn., 1995 Fall (Box 19, Image #950207-14)
  - Farm girl milking, Granite Falls, Minn., 1995 Fall (Box 19, Image #950207-2b)
  - Farmer cleaning his auger, Granite Falls, Minn., 1995 Fall (Box 19, Image #950212-7)
  - Abandoned farmhouse and soybean crop, Tarboro, N.C., 1996 Summer (Box 19, Image #960147-30)
  - Farmer working on his land, Boone County, Ky., 1996 Fall (Box 19, Image #960310-8)
  - Mrs. Douglas and her collards, Columbia, S.C., 1996 Fall (Box 19, Image #960324-10)
  - Crossroads, Estill, S.C., 1998 (Box 19, Image #98022-32a)
  - Untitled, Estill, S.C., 1998 Winter (Box 19, Image #98023-7)
  - House and factory, Estill, S.C., 1998 (Box 19, Image #98025-24)
  - Latino farmworker cleaning out poultry barn in wake of Hurricane Floyd, Tarboro, N.C., 1999 Fall (Box 19, Image #99083-19)
- Correspondence Series, 1995-2009 and undated, 1 folder
  The smallest series within the papers, correspondence includes letters from publishers, event coordination, and donor responses.
  - Correspondence, 1995-2009 and undated (Box 20)
- Printed Material Series, 1976-2008 and undated, 6 boxes
  Printed materials are arranged alphabetically. Larger collections from the same genre or publication are grouped separately. Series described at the folder level.
  - A-B (Box 20)
  - Amberg's promotional packet (Box 20)
  - C (Box 20)
  - Christian publications (Box 20)
  - D-F (Box 20)
  - Exhibit-related printed materials (Box 20)
  - Exhibit-related press coverage (Box 20)
  - Farmers' Legal Action reports, 1988 (Box 20)
  - G-H (Box 21)
  - I-M (Box 21)
  - Luck by Eric Martin (cover only) (Box 21)
  - Music festival brouchures, 1978-2003 (Box 21)
  - N, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - NC Crossroads, 1997-2001 (Box 21)
  - O-P (Box 21)
  - Promotional materials (Box 22)
  - R-Y (Box 22)
  - Rural Advanc e, 1985-1990 (Box 22)
  - Rural Roots, 2000-2001 (Box 22)
  - RAFI Action, 1994-1995 (Box 22)
  - RAFI-USA annual reports, 1996-2008 (Box 22)
  - Reviews of Sodom Laurel Album (Box 22)
  - Southern Changes, 1987-2001, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Southern Exposure, 1984-2003 and undated (Box 23)
  - The Sun, 1993-2004 (Box 23)
  - Theater playbills, 1986 and undated (Box 23)
  - Who is my Neighbor?: Parables of Survival from the Floyd Flood of 1999, 2002 (Box 23)
  - The Arts Journal, 1976-1987 (Box 32)
  - Posters
    - Pultry Worker Justice Legal Advocacy Conference, 2001 Nov. (Box 32)
    - Amberg presentation at Georgia College and State University, 2006 Nov. 13 (Box 32)
    - The New Road Opening Reception and Book Launch, 2009 Nov. 7, 2 copies (Box 32)
    - Blue Wing Valentine Dance, Feb. 16 (Box 32)
    - Madison Celebrates Art Festival, May 17 (Box 32)
    - Mermaids in Marshall, Jun. 11 (Box 32)
    - Studio Sale, Nov. 24-25 (Box 32)
  - North Carolina Independent, 1983-2008 (Box 33)
  - Olé!, 1973 Apr. 21 (Box 33)
  - The Plow, 1976 Sept. (Box 33)
  - SHOTS, 1991 May-Jun. (Box 33)
  - unspecified (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Untitled poster with 16 Amberg photographs (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Poster for Intro Their Labors: Images from Southern-Appalachians exhibit at Landwirtschaftsmuseum in Brunnenburg, 1994 Jun.-Aug., in English and German (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Poster for Traces exhibit at Semi Public in Asheville, N.C., 1999 May 8-30 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Books and Journals, 1996-2008
    - Arts & Letters: Journal of Contemporary Culture, no. 17 (Spring 2007). (Box 28)
    - Arts & Letters: Journal of Contemporary Culture, no. 18 (Fall 2007). (Box 28)
    - Arts & Letters: Journal of Contemporary Culture, no. 19 (Spring 2008). (Box 28)